The German Skynext robot Gatling gun is
swatting Shahids out of the sky in
Ukraine. Ukraine's air force just
dropped fresh footage. That's equal
parts Top Gun and Duck Hunt. It features
something the Russian Ministry of
Defense probably hates more than a rainy
Victory Day parade. The Germanmade
Skynet system absolutely vaporizing Shy
drones over Ukraine. If you like seeing
high-tech gatling guns turn $50,000
kamicazi drones into overpriced
fireworks, stick around. Hey, it's Wes
here, former military guy, law school
grad, and professional seeker of things
that go boom. Now, I've covered the
German Skynext before, but this is not
your rerun. Ukraine's new video is the
first time we're seeing these systems
used in anger, and boy are they
delivering. Let's break down what just
happened. On July 12th, Ukraine's air
force released video showing their
German-made Skynext air defense system
at work. In a location the military
isn't revealing at a time they're not
going to tell us about. Ukrainian crews
lined up Russian Shyhei drones and
started racking up kills like it was ski
season. You can hear the Skynex's
operator. Target hit, target destroyed.
Repeat that at least seven times and you
get the vibe. Ukraine has received two
of these systems so far from Germany,
and based on this footage, they're
earning their keep. The Air Force called
the Skynext's results inspiring. And I'd
say that's an understatement. Unless
your job is flying drones for Russia.
Now, why does this matter so much? Well,
because Russia isn't letting up. We're
talking about mass drone and missile
barges night after night targeting not
just front lines but Kev, Lviv, and
cities deep in the Ukrainian rear. The
Russians keep thinking quantity will be
quality. Just lob enough Shahids at
Ukraine and something will get through.
That's where Skynext changes the math.
Each Shahed cost about 50 grand and
Ukraine can't afford to intercept every
single one with a million dollar
missile. The Skynex is Germany's answer
to what if we just shot down these
things with a robot gatling gun instead.
So what makes the Skynex so effective?
Well, manufactured by Ryan Mal. Yep. The
same company that makes tank guns for
the Abrams and the Leopard. Skynex is a
mobile modular anti-aircraft artillery
system with all components being
containerized for easy transport. The
system uses the Orlicon XAR 3D
situational awareness and detection
radar capable of scanning up to a 50 km
radius. It's controlled via the Orlicon
Skymaster system which manages up to
four 35mm Oricon Mark III revolver gun
air defense cannons simultaneously. In
the US military, we call this type of
system a shore ad for short-range air
defense. This is different though than
traditional anti-aircraft missile
batteries like the Patriot in that the
Skynex is a cannon that uses
programmable air bursting ammunition.
And while a gun can still take down
aircraft, this particular system is
being used in Ukraine to assist with
drone defense. That's not to say the
Skynext can't work together with other
air defense systems. In fact, this is
one of its biggest selling points. This
interoperability allows for seamless
integration into Ukraine's existing
defense infrastructure, enhancing
overall tactical effectiveness. The
systems guns are housed in remotely
controlled turrets equipped with
advanced fire control systems, enabling
automated target acquisition and
engagement. This is all done using
narrow AI at the system level. Skynext
is armed with a variety of ammunition
types also, including the innovative
advanced hit efficiency and destruction
or a head munition. This programmable
ammunition is designed to release a
cloud of sub projectiles at an optimum
range determined by an integrated laser
rangefinder, spraying a cloud of
tungsten projectiles like a claymore
mine in the air to effectively
neutralize both large drones and smaller
UAV swarms. The Orlicon revolver gun
Mark III spits out up to a thousand
rounds per minute with a range of 4 km.
Think of it as a shotgun blast that
covers a whole swarm of drones. The
Skynext's radar tracks the incoming UAV,
calculates the exact moment to detonate
the shell and poof, no more Shahid. The
footage Ukraine released shows exactly
that. Drones dropping one after another
like flies at a bug zapper convention.
But it's not just raw firepower. Skynext
isworked air defense. It can connect
with other sensors, radar, and fire
units. And it's designed to defeat
saturation attacks. Think dozens of
drones coming in at once. This is
layered, modular, and mobile. A system
built for the battlefield of 2025, not
the Gulf War. Perhaps the biggest
advantage of Skynext though compared to
something like the Patriot missile
battery is the speed with which the
system can be packed up and moved to a
new location. In theory, this should
allow Ukraine to experiment with
locations that need them the most. And
this portability also makes them harder
targets for Russian strikes. Not that
Russia would target them anyways, as
they seem happy to attack civilians over
military targets. Wait, why does the
Russian military keep hitting civilian
targets? Oh, because they're right. I
forgot.
High five. All right.
So, why does Berlin keep sending these
things to Ukraine? Because every Skynext
delivered is a direct answer to Russia's
new strategy. Overwhelm the defenders,
break their will, and knock out the
power grid by brute force. Kev's
response is to turn every Shahed raid
into an arms fair for Western systems.
And Skynext just became the poster child
for modern gun-based air defense. Plus,
every time Ukraine posts one of these
videos, it's a recruiting ad for Rhinel
and a warning to the Kremlin. This is
way more than helping Ukraine. It's beta
testing Germany's nextgen air defense in
the world's ugliest proving ground. Of
course, two Skynext systems don't turn
Ukraine into an impenetrable fortress.
There are gaps, big ones. Ukraine needs
dozens, not pairs, if it wants to cover
all of its critical infrastructure. The
reality is that you need layered
defense. Patriots for ballistic
missiles, Iris T and NASAMS for cruise
missiles, and Skynex for drones and
mobile teams for mop-up duty. Right now,
Ukraine is fighting with the world's
most patchwork air defense. But this
patch just got a lot stronger. Here's
the bottom line. Skynex is a lot more
than just a fancy German toy. It's a
necessary, timely, and frankly
satisfying answer to Russia's cheap
drone blitzcream. Every Shahed shot down
is one less apartment block burning. One
more night, the lights stay on in Kev.
So, next time you see a video of a
Ukrainian operator calmly calling target
destroyed, remember that's the sound of
adaptation, innovation, and Germany and
Ukraine quietly sending Russia's drone
war back to the drawing board. That's it
for today. If you learned something new,
consider enlisting in the Wes O'Donnell
channel. Hit subscribe and join the
squad. And as always, glory to Ukraine.
Glory to the heroes. Crimea is Ukraine.
[Music]