[Music]
In a chilling display of modern warfare,
newly released footage Footage from
Ukrainian sources paints a vivid picture
of the relentless drone campaign being
waged against Russian troops on the
front lines. From precision strikes on
armored vehicles to brutal close-range
engagements, the videos provide a rare
and raw glimpse into how drones are
reshaping the battlefield.
In one of the most controversial clips,
an FPV Kamicaza 8 drone hovers just
inches from a motionless Russian soldier
for several ten seconds. The soldier,
visibly broken and unarmed, sits still
as the drone seemingly considers his
fate. Then, without warning, it slams
into his head. A moment that has ignited
debate over the ethics of such strikes.
[Music]
In another encounter, two Russian
soldiers are seen fighting off a
kamicazi drone with their rifles,
narrowly avoiding friendly fire. When
they run out of ammunition, one soldier
throws his rifle at the drone,
triggering a blast at close range. It's
unclear if he survived the explosion.
A dramatic combination of drone and
phone footage captures the moment a
grenade dropped by a Ukrainian drone
explodes near two Russian soldiers
riding a utility vehicle. Injured and
disoriented, they abandon their
transport and flee on foot in search of
help.
Another powerful segment shows a
Ukrainian drone painted in national
colors striking the entrance of an
underground Russian position. Moments
later, dazed Russian troops emerge and
retreat, abandoning their defensive
post.
[Music]
In a desperate act of survival, a
Russian soldier is caught on drone
camera hurling a brick at an incoming
drone. He misses. The drone detonates
with deadly precision.
Elsewhere, a Russian soldier resting
inside a destroyed shipping container
shows no resistance as a Ukrainian drone
sneaks in and explodes, suggesting
either confusion or surrender.
Ukrainian FPV drone operators have also
proven adept at targeting advanced
Russian hardware. Footage shows a T90
tank being picked apart with calculated
drone strikes. After disabling the
engine and optics, a final hit causes
the tank to burst into flames.
Ironically, next to a road sign with a
Ukrainian flag that reads, "Welcome to
Ukraine."
Another
video shows a large group of Russian
troops packed inside a barn just before
it's hit by an incendiary drone. The
resulting fireball collapses the
structure, likely causing numerous
casualties.
[Music]
In a separate strike, Ukrainian forces
target a Russian BTR82 armored vehicle
attempting to recover a tank stuck in
mud. The drone's explosion completely
obliterates the front half of the BTR,
scattering debris across the
battlefield.
[Music]
In yet another incident, three Russian
soldiers retreat to a bunker inside the
ruins of a home. A Ukrainian drone
follows and detonates at the entrance,
collapsing the structure and burying the
soldiers alive.
Drone strikes are also being used to
target strategic assets. In one clip, a
Russian drone operator station is
struck, igniting stored fuel and
ammunition into a raging inferno.
[Music]
Perhaps one of the most surreal moments
is when a Ukrainian FPV drone lands
quietly at the entrance of a Russian
drone base. A soldier steps out,
seemingly mistaking it for a friendly
unit. As he approaches, the drone
detonates in a powerful blast.
Even freshly upgraded Russian armor
isn't spared. AT72 tank, freshly painted
and retrofitted, is quickly immobilized
and destroyed by a combination of FPV
and drone dropped munitions reduced to
twisted metal in minutes.
[Music]
Ukrainian forces faced a surge in combat
activity over the past 24 hours with 200
engagements reported across 11 different
fronts. According to the general staff
of the armed forces of Ukraine, the
Pakovsk front saw the most intense
fighting as Russian troops launched 59
attacks in that direction alone.
Ukrainian military sources report
significant Russian losses with 1,240
troops killed or wounded and over 300
weapon systems and pieces of military
equipment destroyed or disabled during
the fighting.
In the Daetsk region, Ukrainian FPV
drones targeted a building on the
outskirts of Navakatsky where a group of
Russian assault troops had taken cover.
The precision strike collapsed the
structure, burying the soldiers beneath
the rubble, Ukrainian officials said.
Near the village of Ivanki, a Russian
BMP3 infantry fighting vehicle became
stuck in a trench while attempting to
deliver an assault group to the front
line. 12 Russian infantrymen dismounted
and were immediately struck by Ukrainian
drone munitions and artillery fire,
resulting in significant enemy
casualties.
In another incident, Ukrainian FPV
operators foiled a Russian armored push
near Rharifa. The attack began with a
T72B3M
tank equipped with a mine troll,
followed by two BMP2 infantry fighting
vehicles carrying assault troops.
Ukrainian defenders successfully
neutralized the convoy before it could
reach its objective.
[Music]
While Ukrainian forces held firm on
several fronts, the Russian military
made minor territorial gains near Berlin
and along the Novavka front. Ukrainian
commanders confirmed. However, Kiev's
forces also advanced positions on the
Pakovsk front, regaining lost ground
amid sustained fighting. Russian forces
continue to launch combined missile and
drone strikes, targeting Ukrainian
infrastructure and civilian morale in an
apparent effort to erode public resolve
and pressure Western partners. Ukrainian
officials say these hybrid tactics
emphasize the urgent need for continued
international support in the face of
Russia's escalating campaign.
[Music]
Heat.